<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hana Huie</title>
    <description>Hi there! This is the personal site of Hana Huie - student, programmer, and dancer.
</description>
    <link>http://hhuie.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hhuie.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 22:44:10 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 22:44:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>1 Easy Method to Memorize 9 Scales</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you play an instrument or want to learn how, you may be aware of how important scales are. Memorizing and practicing your scales helps improve your technique and playing overall. Here is the trick I used when I played flute to learn and remember my scales!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Note: For the purpose of this post, I will refer to sharp or flat notes as “irregularities” for simplicity’s sake. Also, “#” means a sharp note, and “b” means a flat note.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its essence, this method is based on learning and memorizing scales based on how many sharps or flats they have. For each scale, we will determine how many sharps or flats it has, which notes those irregularities are, and replace the natural notes with either the sharp or flat version of that note, depending on the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the simplest scale to memorize is C. It has no sharps or flats, so it is simply: C D E F G A B C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the other 8 scales, imagine that there are 2 groups of scales: the “Sharps,” and the “Flats.” In the “Sharps” group, the only irregularities a scale will have are sharp notes, and in the “Flats” group, the only irregularities a scale will have are flat notes. In this post, we will memorize 4 scales from each group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each scale in these groups has a certain number of irregularities. What makes them easy to remember is that each scale contains all the irregular (sharp/flat) notes of the scale preceding it in the number of irregularities, and adds on one new sharp or flat irregularity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference this chart, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;# of Irregularities&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Sharp Group&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Flat Group&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Bb&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Eb&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Ab&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confused? Don’t worry! Let’s examine the G and D scales as an example. Notice that G is the first scale in the sharp group, meaning it only has one sharp note and the rest are natural. This one sharp note is F#, which replaces the natural F, so the G scale is: G A B C D E F# G.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to memorize the D scale, we notice that it is the second scale in the sharp group. Thus, it must take on all of the sharps from G, the scale preceding it in number of irregularities. Therefore, we can conclude that the D scale contains the F# that it inherits from the G scale, and adds on one more sharp, which is C#. Thus, the D scale is: D E F# G A B C# D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Here are the 8 “irregular” scales below for your reference:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sharps&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;G, adds F# &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; G A B C D E F# G&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;D, adds C# &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; D E F# G A B C# D&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A, adds G# &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; A B C# D E F# G# A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E, adds D# &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; E F# G# A B C# D# E&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Flats&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;F, adds Bb &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; F G A Bb C D E F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bb, adds Eb &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Bb C D Eb F G A Bb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eb, adds Ab &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Eb F G Ab Bb C D Eb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ab, adds Db &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Ab Bb C Db Eb F G Ab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the most of this method and avoid burnout, here’s my practice recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose to start with either the Sharps group or the Flats group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memorize the first scale of the group (either F for Flats or G for Sharps)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each day, memorize the next scale in the order of irregularities, with the mindset of building upon the “arsenal” of sharps or flats you already know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep practicing and don’t give up! Once you memorize all 4 scales in one group, move on to the next.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;However, don’t forget the scales you learned! When I practiced scales, I used a method in which each day I would practice 2 scales so that every week I would circulate through all of the scales. You can make your own personal schedule for this, or just keep track in your head - whatever works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you go - I hope this helps you out in all of your music-making endeavors. If you have any questions or comments, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me either through email or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/sunshoone&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Hana&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 13:52:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hhuie.github.io/blog/music/2015/05/15/memorizing-scales.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hhuie.github.io/blog/music/2015/05/15/memorizing-scales.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Background Music for Studying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s study time again! In my last post, I talked about the importance of making sure that your environment is set up in a way to help you study. This usually includes background noise, and the right kind of music can really help you focus! Here are my top three music recommendations for studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://songza.com/listen/jazz-for-reading-songza/&quot;&gt;Jazz for Reading Station&lt;/a&gt; on Songza&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this station because the songs are mellow, but not boring. It’s just the right mix of calm and unexpected, which creates the perfect atmosphere for pushing forward and keeping the momentum of your studying going. Also, there are no vocals, so you won’t get distracted while trying to remember if it was the nobles or the peasants who were targeted in the Terror, or while trying to do your Spanish homework. Think of elevator music, but less awkward-eye-contact-avoiding and more excitement to get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/0Gw30FmjnPfqEh75ACEjyh&quot;&gt;Classical Study Music&lt;/a&gt; on Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a fan of classical music, Spotify’s Classical Study Music radio is an obvious choice. Spotify has such a huge variety of classical music; you can also find classical music with specific instruments like piano-only.  like classical music because, like Jazz, there are no vocals to distract you from your thought processes. The only downside to using Spotify is that if you don’t have a premium membership, there will be occasional advertisements that could potentially be distracting. &lt;i&gt;Sigh. Sometimes, the best things in life just aren’t free.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffitivity.com&quot;&gt;Coffitivity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I confess. Coffitivity isn’t music - BUT! It is really an amazing tool and I have gotten so much done using it (hellooo, Comp Sci IA?) Basically, Coffitivity plays the background noise from a coffee shop. The idea behind this technique is that just a &lt;i&gt;little&lt;/i&gt; bit of distraction is good for your brain while you’re working, so that you don’t burn out. Also, an added bonus is that Coffitivity has a free app (&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.coffitivity.coffitivity&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coffitivity/id669576390?mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;)! Now, you can cozy up to the warm sounds of coffee, work, and suburban hipsters wherever and whenever you want. You’re welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, those are my three suggestions for studying music. I hope you give them a try, and if you do, tell me if they work for you! I’ll try to get some comments up on this blog. In the meantime, I wish you the best in all of your studies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Hana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;whoa there, you made it to the bottom of the post! you’re cool. here’s your super secret bonus tip: play more than one background music station at the same time! (if you play the Jazz for Reading station AND Coffitivity at the same time, it sounds like pure heaven on earth. just sayin’.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 07:33:41 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hhuie.github.io/blog/school/2015/05/09/studying-music.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hhuie.github.io/blog/school/2015/05/09/studying-music.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>school</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Studying</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s that time of the year again - AP exams are in 2 days! While I&#39;m sure you&#39;ve done the majority of your studying &lt;i&gt;ahead of time&lt;/i&gt;, I&#39;d still like to share with you 3 of my tips for studying more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Highlight, But Don&#39;t Overdo It!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve all been there - studying our textbook or notes with a highlighter in hand, highlighting almost every line on the page. This is not an effective way to study! Keep your highlighting to cover only &lt;b&gt;1-7 words&lt;/b&gt; (i.e., don&#39;t highlight an entire line - unless if a concept is &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; important). As you read, pay attention to any &lt;b&gt;key concepts&lt;/b&gt; or important &lt;b&gt;vocab terms&lt;/b&gt;. For example, if you were studying some history notes, you would highlight the names of important treaties, names, or acts you might be quizzed on - not necessarily what those treaties were, or what those people did. Keeping it short and concise makes it easier to look back over later. The contrast on the page between black and white notes and a bright highlighted word will make it easier for your eyes to focus on the page, and help you to remember the terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Write in the Margins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you&#39;ve read about an important concept, write a few buzzwords or a &lt;b&gt;short description in your own words&lt;/b&gt; next to that paragraph in the margin briefly summarizing your idea of what it means. This is a great way to solidify any information you&#39;ve learned while reading. It also allows you to easily reference back to a concept that might be mentioned later in the text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Clear Your Studying Environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, I&#39;ve realized that the environment has a huge impact on me when I&#39;m trying to study. I can mostly never study when there are loud noises or conversations going on, and if my desk is very cluttered, I feel claustrophobic and can&#39;t focus on my studying. It is crucial to keep a clean (or at least organized) environment for studying so that you can devote 100% of your attention to memorizing important concepts. Usually, this differs from person to person so keep trying different things until you find what works best for you. Some things you could try are &lt;b&gt;moving to a quiet room, listening to study music or white noise, or completely clearing the surface of your desk&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&#39;s important for us to give our best efforts to our studying because this trains us to give our best efforts to other areas of life in the future, such as our relationships, families, and health. I hope these study tips helped you, and good luck in all of your studies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Hana&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 07:33:51 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hhuie.github.io/blog/school/2015/05/02/3-tips-for-studying.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hhuie.github.io/blog/school/2015/05/02/3-tips-for-studying.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>school</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Post!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://hhuie.github.io&quot;&gt;hhuie.github.io&lt;/a&gt;! As of right now, I am pretty much clueless about markdown. I&#39;ve heard of it before, but I don&#39;t know how it works. But fear not, my dear reader, for this shall soon change! For now, this post is just here to provide a place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for embarking on this journey with me.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 19:25:51 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hhuie.github.io/blog/personal/2015/04/23/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hhuie.github.io/blog/personal/2015/04/23/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
